A Guide to the Fairfax Family Northern Neck Proprietary Papers, 1688-1810
Library of Virginia
- Plats and Surveys, 1741-1793, 8 folders (Folder Box 1, Folder 6 and Box 2, Folder 52-57A)
  - Plats and surveys made by George Murray and John Mauzy, 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 190 acres in Shenandoah County, made by George Murray, 4 August 1787; leased to Henry Keble, etc., 11 August 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 212 acres in Shenandoah County, made by George Murray, 2 August 1787; leased to Moses Henry, etc., 11 August 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 31 August 1787; leased to Tolliver Grigsby, etc., 8 September 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 230 acres (county not stated), made by George Murray, 3 August 1787; leased to John Morehead, etc., 3 September 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 145 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 August 1787; leased to George Asbury, 22 September 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 August 1787; leased to William Shumate, etc., 1 November 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 135 acres in Shenandoah County, made by George Murray, 14 September 1787; leased to John Hambaugh, etc., 6 October 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 250 acres in Shenandoah County, made by George Murray, 15 September 1787; leased to Charles Bagarley, etc., 6 October 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 516 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 12 September 1787; leased to James Davis, etc., 6 October 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 270 acres in Shenandoah County, made by George Murray, 14 September 1787; leased to Jacob Reeder, etc., 6 October 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 235 acres in Shenandoah County, made by George Murray, 15 September 1787; leased to George Cheek, etc., 2 February 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 150 acres in Loudoun County, made by George Murray, 24 September 1787; leased to Jesper Seybold, etc., 1 March 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 84 acres in Loudoun County, made by George Murray, 25 September 1787; leased to Jasper Sibold, etc., 6 October 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 86 acres in Loudoun County, made by George Murray, 25 September 1787; leased to John Wildie, 6 October 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 300 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 25 September 1787; leased to Joseph Corder, 15 December 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 100 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 17 October 1787; leased to Jonathan Potts, Elizabeth, his wife, and son, Joshua, 19 March 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 26 October 1787; leased to William Laurence for three lives, 4 December 1790, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 160 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 26 October 1787; leased to Joseph Walters, etc., 2 May 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 29 October 1787; leased to Joseph Hickman, etc., 7 June 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 90 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 November 1787; leased to Francis Payne for the lives of Presley, Jesse, and Francis, his sons, n.d., 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 80 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 November 1787; leased to Dickerson Wood, etc., 4 July 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 November 1787; leased to Enoch Ashby, etc., 2 February 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 170 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 December 1787; leased to Hugh Bramblet for three lives, 19 February 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 105 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 December 1787; leased to Thomas Watts for three lives, 19 February 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 85 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 20 December 1787; leased to Benjamin Stribling, etc., 4 October 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 71 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 3 April 1788; leased to David Robinson, 5 April 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 3 April 1788; leased to Peter Halley, etc., 3 May 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Frederick and Fauquier Counties, made by George Murray, 5 September 1788; leased to George Leach, etc., 2 May 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 185 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 6 December 1788; leased to Sally Howell, etc., 6 December 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 6 December 1788; leased to Joseph Berry, etc., 6 December 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 6 December 1788; appears to have the name Peter Hitt or Hill on reverse, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 199 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 7 March 1789; leased to Henry Clarkson, etc., 4 July [1789], 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 39 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 7 March 1789; leased to [Christian] Hitch, etc., 4 July [1789], 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 46 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 7 March 1789; leased to [Christian] Hitch, etc., 4 July 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 300 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 22 April 1789; leased to Henry Smith, etc., for three lives, 6 June 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 350 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 22 April 1789; leased to William Mullikin, Sukey Mullikin, his wife, and Nancy Mullikin, his daughter, 2 October 1790, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 40 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 22 April 1789; leased to John Hickman, etc., for three lives, 6 June 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 92 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 22 April 1789; leased to Jeremiah Deerin, etc., 2 May 1789, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 142 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 26 June 1789; possibly leased to Nicholas Lawler, n.d., 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 182 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 26 June 1789; leased to Alexander Welch for three lives, 5 February 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 170 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 26 June 1789; leased to Dennis Grubbs for three lives, 1 January 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 81 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 26 June 1789; leased to Francis Scott for three lives, 19 February 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 42 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 26 June 1789; possibly to Ben Ball, n.d., 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 367 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 26 June 1789; leased to Henry Clarkson, 4 July 1789, 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres (county not specified), made by George Murray, 3 September 1789; leased to Peter Teate for the lives of Peter Teate, Elizabeth Teate, his wife, and [Landy] Teate, his son, 2 October 1790, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 205 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, n.d.; leased to George Page, Molly Page, and George Baylor Page, 3 October 1790, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 135 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 25 September 1790; leased to Thomas Hand for the lives of Thomas Hand, Frances Hand, his wife, and William Hand, his son, 2 October 1790, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by George Murray, 1 February 1791; leased to Richard Carter, n.d., 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 100 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 5 March 1791; leased to Peter Rout, 2 April 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 110 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, n.d.; leased to James Robertson for three lives, 19 February 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 100 acres in Fauquier County, made by John Mauzy for Capt. George Murray, 7 April 1791; leased to Alexander Jeffries for three lives, 15 October 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 146 acres in Fauquier County, made by John Mauzy for Capt. George Murray, 6 April 1791; leased to Daniel Barnes for three lives, 15 October 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 124 acres in Fauquier County, made by John Mauzy for Capt. George Murray, 5 August 1791; leased to William Smith for three lives, 15 October 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 100 acres in Frederick County, made by George Murray, 2 August 1791; leased to John Graves for three lives, 15 October 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 180 acres in Fauquier County, made by John Mauzy for Capt. George Murray, 2 [___] 1791; leased to William Hillary for three lives, 17 December 1791, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 200 acres in Fauquier County, made by John Mauzy, 9 August 1792; leased to John Herndon for three lives, 20 October 1792, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
    - 80 acres in Fauquier County, made by John Mauzy, 12 December 1792; leased to Stephen Bayley for three lives, 6 April 1792, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 57A)
- Legal Papers, 1721-1810, 16 folders (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 58-73)
  - Manuscript legal form, blank, public notice of an escheat, n.d., 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Power of attorney. Thomas Lord Fairfax and William Cage, executor of Catherine Lady Fairfax to Robert Carter, 5 July 1721, 12 p., copy (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Inquisition. Conducted, 14 April 1731, Stafford County, by George Eskridge, Deputy Escheator, and a jury of twelve whose name appear... to determine what lands Massie Ramsey died seized of, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Opinion of Secretary John Carter concerning surveys dated 29 August 1732, 1 p., copy (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Legal opinion of J. Mercer relating to surplus lands and non-payment of quitrents in the Northern Neck, 28 November 1751, 2 p., incomplete (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Copy of record in suit Proprietors vs. Peter Woolf, 1762-1769, 24 p. (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Deposition. Samuel Earle, taken by order of General Court in the cause of Peter Woolf vs. Thomas Lord Fairfax, 7 August 1767; and Deposition. Thomas Lord Fairfax, same cause, [___] February 1764, 3 p., copy (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Deposition. Thomas Bryan Martin, Frederick County, taken before John Hite, Justice of the Peace, 15 April 1769; also, Deposition of Angus McDonald, same date. With endorsement: Thomas Bryan Martin, Northern Neck Proprietors Office, 15 April 1769, 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Acknowledgement. Mary Wilson, daughter of John Hartley, deceased, taken before Okey Johnson, Justice of the Peace, Hampshire County, 16 March 1786, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Deposition. Peter Halley and John Smith, concerning purchase of land. Taken by John S. Woodcock, 11 August 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Award of arbitrators in dispute between Thomas Massie and Merryman Pain, 9 August 1790; signed Jos. Smith, Charles C. Chunn (sic) and John Dyson, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Notification. The Rev. Denny Martin Fairfax to Thomas Brian Martin and others, 1 February 1793; addressees are to cease actions in his behalf. Is selling Leeds and South Branch to James Markham Marshall et als., 3 p. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Articles of agreement between the Rev. Denny Martin Fairfax and James Markham Marshall, 1 February 1793; this item is the enclosure mentioned in No. 16, 5 p., incomplete (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Judgements. Dumfries District Court, 16 October 1793 and 20 October 1794; executors of Thomas Lord Fairfax vs. sundry defendants. Several Judgements., 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Summonses. Three. Frederick County, 9 June 1807, to Daniel Clarke, John Walls, and Christopher Whitzel, 3 p. (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Chancery Bill. To the High Court of Chancery held at Staunton, Brownley's executors vs. Woodcock's executors, 18 May 1810, 3 p., copy (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Letters, 1743-1785, 9 folders (Box-folder Box2, Folder 74-82)
  - Charles Carter [illegible] to William Fairfax, Mount Vernon, Fairfax County, 20 August 1743, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - H Thacker to [___], 4 February 1744, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Richard Barnes to [___], 13 May 1749, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Jost Hite? to Thomas Lord Fairfax, 2 September 1749, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Col. B. Martin to George William Fairfax, Belvoir, 10 February 1768, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Bryan Fairfax, Towlston, to [B. Martin?], 9 October 1783, 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - B. Martin, Greenway Court, to [Bryan Fairfax?], 19 October 1783, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Gabriel Jones to Thomas Bryan Martin, Greenway Court, 15 April 1784, 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Robert Adams, Alexandria, to Bryan Martin, near Winchester, 25 April 1784, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Bryan Martin, Towlston, to Thomas Bryan Martin, Greenway Court, Frederick [County], 27 October 1785, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Miscellaneous, 1693-1788, 22 folders (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 83-104)
  - Account of Lands [per order of] Mr. Landon Carter, Prince William, Richmond, Westmoreland, and Northumberland counties, n.d., 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Petition to Lord Fairfax from unidentified person, endorsed "for Mr. G. Wythe," n.d., 1 sheet (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Fragment of lower half of "Recorded in the Council Books according to order the 26th October 1693", 1 p., copy (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Account of Col. William Ball's land, 1737, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Petition, Thomas Lord Fairfax to the Lords Commissioners of his Majesties Treasury, [1746], 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Report. Hugh Walpole to the Lords Commissioners of his Majesties Treasury regarding petition of Lord Fairfax, 26 April 1746, 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Account. John Grymes, Receiver General in account with Thomas Lord Fairfax, 25 April 1747, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Memo. Lands of Col. William Fitzhugh, 25 November 1749, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Addition and subtraction, n.d., 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - A memorandum of entrys desired to be made by Sundry Persons, 1754, 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - A list of entrys taken on the Cacape [Tr?]ons in Hampshire in the Spring 1754 by John Mauzy, 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - A list of entrys taken by John Mauzy in the Spring 1754, 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Memorandum. Quitrents owned by Capt. Daniel McCarthy, Dennis McCarthy, and Thaddeus McCarthy through the year 1756, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Advertisement. Northern Neck of Virginia Lord Proprietor's office. Warning against assignment of land. Signed B. Martin, 26 March 1765, 1 p., copy (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Receipt. Turner Crump to Thomas Lord Fairfax, 5 February 1768; and same to Thomas Bryan Martin, 31 May 1768, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Bill of sale for a "negro" slave. John White, Frederick County, to Joseph King, Frederick County, 22 September [1768], 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Receipts: William Allason to Thomas Lord Fairfax, Greenway Court, 4 December 1769; and William Allason to Thomas B. Martin, Greenway Court, 4 December 1769, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Bill of sale for "negro" slaves. William Clark, King George County, to Thomas Bryan Martin, Frederick County, 22 December 1770, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Bill of sale for a "negro" slave. Humphrey Messenborough, Town of Norfolk, to William Allason, Town of Falmouth, King George County, 22 March 1771, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Bill of sale for "negro" slaves. William Daingerfield, Spotsylvania County, to William Allason, King George County, 21 June 1771, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Plan of the town of Bath (now Berkeley Springs, West Virginia), showing steet, lots, etc., with endorsements, n.d., 2 p.; This town was laid out in 1776. George Washington purchased lots 58 and 59. (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - William Helm and Samuel Knight's assess roll commencing 19 May 1778," [Frederick?], 18 p. (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Certification. J. Moffett stating that in 1759 Bailey Johnson had a grant, 17 March 1787, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Statement of John Oldacre, concerning John Danks, 1 March 1788, 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 104)